JENNY WILLIAMS



I am a curious seeker after truth, who loves the challenge of delivering creative, commercially sound communication strategies that help brands and consumers connect. I believe that true integration is no longer an optional approach to delivering brand engagement but is at the heart of every successful campaign.

My curiosity and appetite for challenge has meant that my experience portfolio is very broad. In a nutshell I've done everything from delivering the strategic inspiration for the Pet Food aisle of the future for Australia's largest grocer, to delivering the global launch campaign for a drug that can offer early stage COPD patients more of their life back, as well as lots of experience in the booze and soft drinks categories as well as FMCG generally.

Along the way I have developed an extensive strategy skill set, encompassing Customer Journey and Engagement Planning, Behavioural Economics "nudge" application and Shopper / Retail Marketing.

EDUCATION

MBA - Warwick University 1987

BA Hons (1st Class)- Business Studies University of South Wales 1986

SKILLS

Producer of single minded and inspiring Creative Briefs / Briefing Sessions	Extensive experience within brand and strategic planning across a wide variety of markets including Retail, FMCG, Pharma and Leisure
Effective leader of the brand and comms planning process, with the skill set to deliver clear strategies and compelling activation platforms	Deep understanding of a variety of disciplines including Retail / Shopper Marketing, Pharma / B2B and Experiential
Creative advocate with an ability to quickly identify the central core of a creative idea and deliver constructive builds and critiques	Application of Behavioural Economics principles as a framework for driving behavioural change
Solid grounding in Market Research craft skills: Questionnaire / Discussion Guide design, Focus Group Moderation, and Data / Insight Analysis and Debriefing	Experienced in CX strategic development process, including persona creation and customer journey mapping
Experienced workshop moderator including creative ideation and inspiration sessions	Skilled in TTL Comms planning, with the ability to "join the dots" in the complex integrated media environment (on and offline) to ensure a cohesive messaging and activation strategy
Author of think pieces and RFP content that have successfully attracted new clients	Versatile skill set and extensive experience ensures success in a wide variety of strategic projects from Brand development to creative strategies and activation / comms planning

WORK HISTORY

2021 - STRATEGY DIRECTOR FISHWACK HEALTH
Client Responsibilities

JANSSEN IMBRUVICA: Leading the EMEA brand and communication strategy for the market leading novel targeted therapy that offers game changing survival for CLL patients

2020-21 ASSOCIATE PLANNING DIRECTOR PUBLICIS LIFE BRANDS / LANGLAND

Client Responsibilities

GSK ANORO: Delivering the creative strategy for a fully integrated Global HCP campaign to support ANORO, a COPD treatment that delivers superior effectiveness in early treatment of COPD

GSK ANORO: Supporting the brand's shift to a modular content strategy through the development of CJM and associated messaging for key HCP segments

GSK Zejula: Developing the creative and communications strategy for the delivery of an unbranded communications campaign designed to reshape the market and help HCP's understand the choices they have in the treatment of advanced Ovarian Cancer

GSK Zejula: facilitation of remote Brand Personality workshop, designed to create cross functional alignment around the Zejula brand archetype

Pitch Win

DHL LSH: Creating a pitch winning global communication strategy for the Life Sciences logistics sector of the global logistics giant

2018-2019 FREELANCE SENIOR STRATEGIST / STRATEGY DIRECTOR

Agency Clients

- Unit 9: Building an experiential strategy for a leading HNB smoking substitute
- We Are Alexander: Developing brand positionings / activation platforms for a variety of brands within the ABI Craft / International Beer portfolio
- Leagas Delaney: NPD and Global comms positioning for one of the world's largest vape brands

2016-2018 STRATEGY DIRECTOR TSA SYDNEY

Pitch Wins

Real Pet Food Company: Created a new Comms platform for Nature's Gift natural dog food, a challenger brand within the category

Diageo: Successfully launched Australia's first premium pre-mix: Tanqueray & Tonic

Heinemann Duty Free: Delivered a new Retail Comms campaign to support Heinemann's entry into the Australian market

Saputo Dairy: Created a disruptive new positioning for Liddells Lactose Free to create new interest in Lactose Free dairy

Saputo Dairy: Created new behavioural cues for Devondale Butter Spread to drive increased consumption Research & Consultancy

Ferrero Rocher: Understanding occasionality drivers for Confectionary **Diageo**: Understanding and reaching Millennials in the alcohol category

Coke: Key Activation Period strategies to drive increased soft drink consumption

Client Workshops

CUB: Debunking Shopper Marketing Myths **Heinemann**: Creative Strategy and Ideation

2014 - 2016 STRATEGY DIRECTOR MCCANN WORLDWIDE GROUP DUBAI

Strategy Director across 3 agencies within the MCN group, spanning ATL / TTL (Promoseven 360) Healthcare (McCann Health) and Digital / Customer Experience (MRM).

Pitch Wins

RAK Bank: Created a Premium Banking TTL campaign designed to appeal to aspiring HNW consumers

Dubai Aquarium: Created an ATL campaign to help Dubai Aquarium stand out in the crowded leisure attractions marketplace

Boehringer Ingelheim OTC Healthcare: Created locally relevant TTL campaigns that made the most effective use of global assets

Customer Experience

General Motors: Regional Strategy lead for Global CX project for GM dealership network, designed to maximise the profit generated by dealers.

Led strategy input including persona generation, workshopping, customer journey mapping and research analysis

2013-2014 PLANNING DIRECTOR GEOMETRY GLOBAL / LIFE AGENCY / QUIET STORM

Pitch Wins

Visa: Created the in-store Path to Purchase strategy for a promotional activation for Visa designed to encourage uptake of Contactless payments by leveraging Visa's World Cup sponsorship equity

GSK: Drove the creative and touchpoint strategy for the launch of a new Ribena variant in convenience, via messaging designed to appeal to the Millennial target audience

2011-2013 DEPUTY PLANNING DIRECTOR THE MARKETING STORE

Pitch Wins

- **Weetabix**: Successfully delivered an integrated campaign designed to bring the brand's fuel positioning to life TTL Research and Strategy
 - Marks & Spencer: Delivered a well- received promotional strategy designed to address three key issues for the retailer:
 - Revitalising Dine In for 10 Pounds
 - Promotional support for Ladies Fashion
 - Leveraging Summer 2012

Intellectual Property

- Kids & Shopping: A gual pilot study that examined the effect that kids have on grocery buying behaviour
- The Future of Shopping: An experiential workshop designed to immerse guests in the Shopping experiences of the future

2006-2011 SENIOR PLANNER ARC WORLDWIDE

Pitch Wins

• **Coke**: Strategies for tailor made promotional support for key Coke activations, including Fanta and Halloween and Coke Sponsorship tie-ups

Brand Support

- **Philip Morris International**: Delivered packaging and branding strategy for Bright Leaf, the first Marlboro NPD variant to be launched for a decade
- Kraft: Created integrated strategies designed to create stand out in the coffee category for Kenco and Carte Noir
- P&G: Created global Shopper Marketing toolkits for Always femcare